you everyone for joining us here at
first pull request live on Zoom this is
a world premiere
the world premiere of a just you know
little workshop that Simon and I had put
together that really just kind of grows
out of some you know my our own activity
as people who really love and want to
promote open source software and kind of
like a little tradition in the data
journalism world where I came up of you
know peers teaching peers and you know
once we learn how to do something we try
to share it with as many other people as
possible and so really the goal of this
is really just to share
um kind of what we see as a basic
fundamental skill of Open Source
software
um to help to help others learn it uh I
think we can get through the course
materials in 60 to 90 minutes maybe even
faster just kind of depending on how
things go but I am not in a hurry at all
and so we can go at whatever Pace works
for you or just for the material
because it is our first time teaching it
there will definitely be a few hinks and
bugs and so I appreciate your patience
at the outset
um I should probably introduce myself my
name is Ben Welsh I'm broadcasting to
you live from Little Tokyo in downtown
Los Angeles I have been a data
journalist at the Los Angeles Times for
15 years next week this year I'm
currently on a fellowship at Stanford
University where I'm working working in
partnership with the journalism school
there on a project called Big local news
which tries to make data tool and tools
to work with data more accessible to the
local newsrooms across the world I am
joined by my co-instructor Simon
Willison Simon would you care to
introduce yourself sure yeah my name's
Simon Willison I've been an open source
developer for nearly 20 years I think I
worked on what became Django the web
framework more recently I spent the past
five years working on a project called
dataset which is open source software
aimed at helping people will analyze and
publish their data I did a Stanford
Fellowship a few years ago which
completely ruined me because I got to
work on whatever I thought was
interesting and I've continued to do
that unpaid ever since so I'm coming to
you from uh Half Moon Bay just south of
San Francisco and yeah I'm uh I've
always been I I spent a lot of my career
journalism adjacent I like writing tools
and writing software that journalists
can use so this this Workshop meshes two
of my interests really well
all right well thank you for joining us
so Simon will just be here chiming in
and correcting all my mistakes and um
and helping me kind of work us through
this material obviously you know
um
uh uh uh I do not obviously but let me
just say please interrupt us or ask
questions or speak up as we go through
this stuff we want to make sure that you
guys get it there's five to ten pieces
of absolutely outrageous nerd jargon
that we're gonna have to like try to
struggle to define and explain and I'm
sure we won't be perfect at it or we
might use some other weird terms that
you haven't encountered before and if we
do just stop us or just ask you can just
honestly just interrupt over the
microphone is fine or just toss
something in the chat whatever you're
comfortable with
um and that's it so um that's the that's
the deal My Hope Is we can work through
this and the goal is to show you how to
uh make changes to open source software
to look at the code that other folks
have published on the web make a tweak
and suggest that they include it and
this that process is called a pull
request when it's done via the website
github.com which is the most popular
code management site there's other words
for it that's what GitHub calls it and
our goal is to teach you how to do that
today and this technique is really a
basic skill of software development that
if you are interested in becoming a
developer or just a hobbyist who
contributes to code you're going to want
to learn and um for the purposes of the
demonstration everyone who works through
the class will make a pull request today
to an open source website that I
maintain which we'll look at in a minute
before we get into that I'd like
everybody to go to the web address that
I've put right here in our little help
file and it is at bit dot lead slash
first hyphen PR and PR is a common piece
of slang for a pull request right so
there's a there's our first gunky jargon
so it's bit dot Lee slash first hyphen
PR and if you go there you'll see the
script we wrote which we're going to
walk through together which contains
everything we're going to cover
now before I launch into that
I want to open it up to everybody who's
come to see if there's any questions so
before we begin does anybody have any uh
any questions about
um the class or just things in general
no okay
Arky I see you shared the link is that
working for you
I I'll take that as a yes all right
everybody so here we go on the site
let's begin so in the first chapter we
kind of cover what we're going to do
here and that is of course make this
code contribution which is known as a
pull request the site that everyone will
be contributing to is called the EE
Cummings free Poetry archive this is a
website that's at the Domain cummings.e
and it everything about this website is
open source software that is hosted on
GitHub and that anyone can contribute to
and the mission of this site
um is to transcribe the Poetry of EE
Cummings as it gradually enters the
public domain
uh the way that copyright law works in
the United States is that after a work
is created uh it is protected legally as
the intellectual property of the author
or the owner of it but then after a
certain number of years it expires and
it enters What's called the public
domain which it effectively becomes open
source of its own and anyone is able to
resell repackage or remix it in any way
they like we're in an interesting moment
now which is each January 1st when the
next year of old material goes live
we're gradually crawling through the
1920s right now here in the United
States which means that many works of
modernist poetry uh early Cinema uh and
uh and early popular music are beginning
to enter the public domain famously last
year the Great Gatsby became a public
domain item and so you can look forward
to
Simon's graphic novel casting his pets
in The Great Gatsby or I don't know what
exactly right but whatever you would
want to do would be uh totally uh free
at this point and as someone who loves
open source dog software but also a
public domain and is a little bit of an
amateur archivist I just took on as a
hobby during the pandemic the um
the the mission of trying to open up EE
Cummings work and so for the last couple
of years I've been leading the drive to
gradually enter all of the poems into
the site as they open and this year on
January 1st a book that came out in 1926
called is five which is the fourth book
by E Cummings entered the public domain
it has 88 poems in the book and
currently only 28 of them have been
entered into the website which is really
just the process of transcription
um I've gone to the Los Angeles Public
Library the Central Library downtown
where they have a first edition of the
book and I scanned that in and uploaded
it to the internet archive and so the
process isn't that beautiful the process
of um transcription is really taking the
copy that appears in these scans and
keep punching them into a computer file
that can go into the website okay and
that's all done on github.com Via what's
called a code repository which I'm
looking at right here Simon how would
you define a code Repository
so a repository it's
that's a really trick that's a
surprisingly tricky question it's like a
folder it's a directory on a computer
where it would be a product where you
keep all of the code that exists in a
single project
um with with a GitHub repository that's
that's the thing that you've then
published and either publicly so anyone
can see it or GitHub also lets you have
private repositories that you can use to
collaborate with other people so um
there are there are people who will
debate how much should go into
repository let's say put everything that
your company does in a single repository
have a they call it a um a mono
repository this is not a debate for
today for for our purposes something
like cummings.ee is a perfect example of
the size of project you might want to
have an individual project uh repository
for
right so all the code that makes the
website that we're looking at right here
everything that puts this together is
contained within this kind of magic
folder hosted by github.com and because
I've made the code open source AKA open
to the Public's review I'm actually able
to host it for free which is one of the
nice things about GitHub and one of the
chief reasons why it's become the
dominant place to find open source
software in a sense GitHub is
effectively a social network for these
these code repositories or these folders
and So within this website you can find
the code that powers Django the project
that Simon worked on you can find the
code that um
that that what was on the initial space
the initial space missions from NASA you
can find the code that runs inside of
your smart watch and just literally tens
of thousands or hundreds of thousands of
software projects each have a page like
this one that's Project Specific where
they store all of the files that kind of
make the application but then they also
collaborate with other developers to
carefully make changes to that code
using a system called Version Control
which is just really computer
programming tricks for very carefully
managing edits to individual files to
make sure you don't break the code or
the two people don't make conflicting
changes
uh any questions about GitHub or
repositories
no okay so yeah
by GitHub is there any good tutorial or
book to explain this because every time
I've tried to learn it I've just given
up
and you get stuck with trying to like uh
create a repository with your terminal
or where do you get where do you get
caught up
um
I usually lose track of how to make the
whole thing work
yeah I mean it's just it's it's one of
these things that's especially tricky
because you have on the web you have
this magic folder that exists also as a
web page or thing but then traditionally
when you're then working on those code
files you have to have a copy of those
files on your computer as well right and
so part of the dance of computer
programming traditionally has been the
to and fro of the changes that you make
on your computer versus what you submit
and send to the sort of origin as they
call it the sort of Mothership
repository that's on the web
go ahead Simon so um GitHub is the
website git is the software you use to
manage the changes git has notoriously
it's one of the hardest pieces of
software to use in all of computer
programming like I've been using it for
probably 15 years I use about five
percent of the functionality and I
frequently find myself getting confused
when I dive into some of the more
complicated belts oh good it's not just
me no oh no that's really important to
understand it it is a nightmare to use
yes everyone acknowledges that the thing
is that because we all use it it's
difficult to adopt something else and
what we're going to show you today is
ways to use the GitHub web interface to
avoid quite a lot of the horrors of
having to use git so this Workshop you
won't be having to open a terminal at
all but you'll still be able to create
edits and propose changes that's exactly
right and and like I think Ron that the
terminal stuff I've seen trip up
literally hundreds of students teaching
this stuff if that's where you're having
trouble I think the stuff we'll cover
today which is pretty new technology
will keep you entirely in the browser
and I think you can do quite a lot of
coding that way it kind of depends what
you're trying to do
um but if you want something that's in
between everything in the browser and
the hell of the terminal there's an
application called GitHub desktop and
it's really intended to be a bridge
between the copy that's on your computer
and the copy that's on the web and I
know that quite a lot of developers even
people who are very skilled with the
terminal prefer tools like that just
because they think they're easier
and so my advice would be to seek out
GitHub desktop Beyond this class perhaps
also github.com has a pretty excellent
help section and if you haven't looked
at it in a while I would just go look at
their really introductory materials like
how do I even get started and I bet you
um it would be more helpful than the
last time you looked
all right
so now the thing I need everyone to do
is to log into github.com so if you
already have an account great just log
into it if you don't I need you to make
one now okay and I am going to open up
an incognito web browser and try to do
that myself okay
I think I have
an account I made for this but let's see
if it shows up
uh here's an older one maybe I can use
that
because I need to log in as just like a
as a regular old user like you guys not
as the administrator of
uh the the cummings.ee repository
because I'm the administrator that I
have special powers that the average
person on GitHub doesn't if you think
about it
um
if you think about it
um repository can be open source it can
be legible and readable and accessible
to all people but you can't let edits to
the code be accessible to all people
because then anybody could hack
everything right and so the way that
open source software is managed you know
as as well as it is managed is that you
have a group of sort of super users who
are often called maintainers or owners
and they are the ones who manage what is
allowed to be let into the sort of main
or Master collection of code in the
repository and then everyone else as an
outsider is allowed to read the code to
run the code on their own independently
right but then also make changes and
suggest those changes go back into the
process right and that is where the
maintainers then come in to try to fix
it and we'll see how all that works okay
so I'm going to make a new
GitHub account right here
that needs a number okay
you can you guys can watch me flail
okay
uh
how about that okay I'm gonna generate a
password
there we go
there we go what should my news username
be guys
uh first PR see if you can get that one
ah how about that
uh I do not want emails no
all right then you have to solve a
little puzzle this is where we prove
we're human I think it's that one
and then it's this one the piggies
okay now we've created our account
it's gonna email me something okay let's
see if I get that email a launch code I
haven't seen this this flow in a very
long time they've done all sorts of
things to it yeah
there's my okay I just got the email it
is 916-10570
okay 50 plus
okay
sorry as a person who works with data
all day I love to pollute other people's
data
um it's not a nice thing about me okay
continue for free
whoa GitHub whoa that's that's what
Microsoft pays for right there dude
all right so we're in I now have a
totally blank GitHub
um account right I'm a total newbie on
the site you can see in the upper right
there's ways to customize your account
if you haven't done it I'd recommend
turning on two-factor authentication
though I won't do that here today and
you can see there's really not a lot
going on here but one of the first
buttons that's available to you is
create a repository right because that's
one of the that's what GitHub is for is
to create these code folders and so if
you wanted to you could create a public
or private uh Repository
they hold your hold your work you don't
need to do that here for today but just
this is just an example of kind of why
it's there and now we'll see if I go to
the address
for
um cummings.ee
um what I see here is slightly different
than in my other browser tab where I am
an administrator where here you can see
there's a settings thing that allows me
to muck with the repo and here you can
see there is not right because now I'm
an outsider contributor I'm not the
maintainer and so what I can do is a
little more restricted
all right so has everybody been able or
already have a GitHub account are we all
into the site and ready to go
great I see some thumbs up
if anybody's having issues it's totally
fine just feel free to speak up
if you haven't done it yet in chapter
two of the class there's a link down
here at the bottom that goes to the code
repository I'd just like you to open
that in a tab so that you're in the same
place that I am right here okay once you
have that up you have the Repository
okay
so once we have the code we should maybe
like look at what's actually in here a
little bit you can see a sort of
directory structure like you would find
on your Windows or Apple computer
um where it sort of has files and
folders that are organized
um within like a little tree structure
pretty traditional stuff
um this particular collection of files
is everything necessary to build the
website and it's organized into what's
called a generically a framework a
framework is just like a tool belt of
code that's been put together by other
developers to make it easier to just get
stuff done so Django which Simon
mentioned is what you might call a
framework it's a bunch of python code
that does a million different things
that make it easier to build a dynamic
website as well as do other things
um you may have heard of other
Frameworks called like Ruby on Rails or
react or Gatsby and these are all just
different sort of competing systems in
different programming languages to
create uh you know tool belts that make
it easier to get stuff done and it just
so happens it's not that important but
it just so happens that this repository
in this website uses a framework called
Baker which was invented at the Los
Angeles Times to help us build all of
our special projects and so you know you
want to do live election results outside
of the content management system or a
big long beautiful scrolling feature
right you might need to write your own
custom code and so Baker was the tool
that we wrote to do that it's in use
currently at the LA times as well as at
propublica the Baltimore banner and the
city uh if you're interested in learning
more about Baker we have a whole
separate class about that which I taught
at the night car conference last year
it's called first visual story and it
will guide you through how to use Baker
or really any uh sort of static site
framework because it's called to build
your own custom page that you can
publish outside of the outside of the
content management system where you work
or just really your own micro site and
so because I was familiar with using
that at the LA Times I used it to make
this little microsite cummings.ee and it
really can be used to make almost any
website if you used it properly so we
don't need to learn everything about how
it works but you know one challenge of
contributing to an open source project
is even if you just want to correct a
typo or add a very narrow feature or fix
a small bug you do kind of have to go
through the sort of like sussing out
process of like how has this thing even
put together and where are all our other
things and sort of gradually learning
kind of the system by which the
developers have put hello and welcome to
git and GitHub for poets this is
and
um
and uh and you can and so here we won't
cover everything that has to do with it
but I can just tell you that
in the underscore data folder
there's another folder called poems I
just ask everybody to click in here and
then into is five right and so I just
happen to know this is the place to go
because I created this repository and so
in the data directory there's a there's
a there's a folder for each of the four
books that we've entered and then in
each of those there's a file for each of
the poems right and so uh we could see
that for instance in the first file that
we're looking at which is for the the
first poem and the five American series
we could see a file that contains the
poem and some extra metadata if I go to
cummings.ee
and I click into the location of that
same poem here we can see that the exact
same stuff
that's on the page is in that data file
and the way that the website works which
we won't cover in in any depth is it
really it takes the data from these
files and it templates them into the
website and that's how this kind of site
works it's using that particular
framework all of those things are just
opinionated decisions I made as the
initial developer and are up for debate
but you know part of figuring out or
contributing to somebody else's code is
kind of like sniffing around how it's
set up and figuring out what you might
want to do or don't do like Simon when
you first encounter someone else's code
how do you figure out what it's doing
but it depends on which programming
language they're using if it's a
JavaScript thing there's a file called
package.json you can go and look at if
it's python you can look at
requirements.txt but generally I hope
that they've got a readme that explains
what's going on so the good projects do
a lot of projects don't bother and then
often what I'll do is I'll actually use
the GitHub search interface so I'll say
okay I know that there's a poem that
uses the word uses the the word sinuous
in there I will search for sinuous and
that will show me which file here we go
and so now I've gone from looking at the
front page we're actually having an idea
of how this thing is structured so often
I I will I will use github's code search
quite extensively just to try and figure
out okay this thing I want to this this
page on the website where is that in the
repository and that'll get me there
really quickly mm-hmm student
and then also if you're looking to
contribute a really natural place to
look is What's called the issue tracker
or the issues tab so if you see here in
the upper left where my mouse is there's
just a little link that says issue with
I guess a bullseye I'm not even sure I
know what that is
um and in it and this is like you know
like you might have in your work uh
workplace if you work anywhere close to
software this is sort of an open source
version of a classic ticket manager like
you might have um in jira or any other
of those tools like that and it's really
a place where the maintainers of a
project but also the users
um can uh can raise bugs can propose
features can hold discussions about what
to do with the website and it is a venue
for kind of managing
um little changes that get made to the
code over time right I'm going to set a
quick plug for GitHub issues if you've
used Jerry you probably hate jira I I
don't think I've ever met somebody who
who didn't absolutely despise it it does
the job GitHub issues is the only issue
tracker I've used that I don't hate and
this is this is high price indeed I've
run my life out of it I've got like
private GitHub repositories for
households chores and things that use
GitHub issues because it works so well
for me
yeah it's pretty nice tool and just to
show it like on another project an open
source project you've probably heard
something about in the last few months
is Mastodon which is an attempt to
create an open source competitor to
Twitter
and you can see here this is of course a
very active project that's been around a
number of years and you see here if you
look in their issues tracker you'll see
that there's more than 3 000 issues
where people all around the world who
are surging into the site have been
suggesting things I think I have one in
here if we search for me
let's see if we can find it
no how do you filter for person can I
use a colon pale wire
oh no that didn't work at all that's
everything
your issues how about that there we go
if that worked no hmm I definitely filed
a bug whatever oh I'm not logged in as
me I'm logged in as this other weird guy
there you go that makes sense
ah
so just to just to like make the point I
was using Mastodon as I'm as I'm
exploring it like everyone else in the
world and uh I thought I found what I
thought to be a bug which was that um in
the color choice that they had made for
kind of the toot button uh wasn't
passing a certain kind of accessibility
test not that it was such a crime or
whatever and so what I did is I went
into their issue tracker and I tried to
document this bug right and so it was
just like hey I ran this kind of this
one particular test for accessibility I
found that uh the colors are you know
totally up to Snuff uh I did an
experiment where maybe we could change
it to something else it's within the
color scheme and so hey what do you
think of that idea right and so this is
basically me filing a bug report with
the the owners of this repository and
just kind of seeing what they think
trying to document what I was thinking
so that you know they don't have to read
my mind and you know somebody might get
around to it at some point I think this
particular group of developers is pretty
flooded with activity and so I don't
really blame them for not having got to
it yet but that's an example of kind of
a real life bug report that I made
myself right and then the pull request
or the change would be intended to
address that right and so issues are
often the targets of pull requests or
code changes where you're saying well we
have this particular issue that we want
to address I've got the code that's
intended to address it and those two
things kind of go together and so if we
look back at the cummings.ee
issue tracker I've created a couple
dozen tickets right here for individual
poems that are missing from the website
right so if we look at the page for is
five on cummings.ee we can see that only
28 of the books 88 poems have been
entered there's 60 to go and the ones
that haven't been entered are grayed out
in the table of contents right and what
I've done is I went through and picked
about 20 that aren't very long and made
tickets for each of them
and then in each ticket I included a
link to the file in the file system
where the where the poem should go and a
link to the scan from the LA Public
Library where the poem it appears on the
page right and so what I'm now going to
ask is that we just kind of go through
everybody who's here as a participant
and we kind of assign different people
tickets right and there actually is a
system for doing this within
um the issue tracker which I'll show
with like I'll use Simon as my example
Simon you're going to enter one right uh
definitely yep okay so I'm gonna go down
to the one at the bottom and just start
there and I'm going to say supposing I
dreamed this is going to be Simon's
assignment and um within the interface
of the ticket there's ways for tagging
things and grouping them and then
there's also a way of assigning people
to manage the uh ticket is that your
username Simon no I don't think it's
going to let you because I'm not a
current participant in this response
tree that's annoying so okay
it looks like you have to add people as
maintainers so maybe the assigning
function isn't quite going to work we
can assign with comments instead yeah so
I'm going to say Simon you want to take
this one and then here you can see
there's kind of a comment thread that
referrals in the issues where you can
have a discussion about what's going on
so Simon's going to take that one
um let me just call up our chat and we
have 10 folks in the chat I'm just going
to go through everybody and uh assign
each of you one to manage I won't tag
you or do whatever we'll just I just
want to make sure we don't have two
people doing the same poem is all right
and this is where the software can
really be helpful for divvying things up
so that you know people don't end up
repeating each other's work and so just
looking at our class list Ron you're the
next one on the list
Ron I'm gonna give you nobody wears a
yellow that's ticket number one eight
two okay
all right
next on the list is Adrian Adrian I'm
gonna give you it is so long since my
heart has been with yours that's ticket
number one eight three all right
Archie Archie I'm gonna give you number
one eight four which is if within
tonight's erect if within tonight's
erect goes to arkey at number 184
Jose you're going to get number 185
which is I go to this window
Arky is number one eight five
that's Jose Jose's number 185 arky's
number one eight four
Michael you're going to be number 186
which is touching you I say it being
spring
being one of the classic words in ee
Comics poetry recurs Through The Years
in many many poems touching you I say it
being spring goes to Michael
Sean you got number one eight seven
that's our touching Hearts slenderly
comprehend
our touching Hearts slenderly comprehend
number 187 goes to Sean and then Tom
I've got you at number 189 with poets
yegs and thirsties Poets yangs and
thirsties number 189 goes to Tom okay so
you can go in and you can leave a
comment if you just want to mark it but
what I really ask you to do for instance
Tom is to go in here and open these two
links into two different tabs so that
you have both the empty file and the uh
the poem you're gonna transcribe I'm
gonna give myself a poem
um
yes
I'm going to go with reasoned
irrefutable unastered
all right which I hope is not how you
feel after this class
that's going to be assigned to me and
just to kind of make the Point tickets
can be assigned once you're associated
with a repository there's kind of a
process here for just like tagging
people and sticking them in and now this
ticket belongs to me right and there's a
whole set of buttons and things to do
all kinds of stuff with issues and to
manage them
all right
so everybody's got their issue
Okay cool so now we're almost ready to
begin work there's just one more piece
of jargony software we got to cover
which is yaml okay so you yaml y-a-m-l
you can see it in the file extension of
your poetry file Simon what's yaml
yaml ain't a mock-up language or very
there have been various acronyms over
time the most recent one is that
right so yaml is it's it's a file format
it's an acronym and it's really just a
data storage language that is used
across a lot of different programming
domains in different places just to hold
data and it's so it's sort of like a
single row in a spreadsheet is one way
to think about a yaml file it can do
more than that but that's one way to
think about it and each one of these
yaml files contains all the metadata
necessary for an individual poem just to
refer back to the one we were looking at
initially you can see that the title of
the poem is there the first line of the
poem is there which is in an index
Elsewhere on the site and then most
importantly the content of the poem is
in an attribute called text so the the
the value that's before the colon is
like the name of the column or the name
of the the the the the key of the value
and then following the colon is the
value itself and you can see in our
documentation that yaml supports you
know uh strings numbers and then lists
and also nested uh objects as well and
so you can kind of use yaml to structure
kind of whatever you want right but in
the case of the Cummings ee repository
it's intended to structure a poem right
so I sort of invented a very simple uh
set of metadata for storing those pumps
and so our mission is going to be to
edit the yaml file that you've been
assigned right and mine was
uh this one to add that text attribute
and then to type in the poem all right
so
let's do it Sean you raised your hand
what's up man
I was just curious if you could mention
what part of your code is parsing the
yaml text strings and actually putting
them like turning them into HTML on the
website just for reference later I'd be
curious of course so the underscore data
folder in a baker project this is
something particular to Baker right so
in the baker framework any file that's
put into the underscore data folder is
parsed by the framework and converted
into like an object that then can be put
onto the page you're making right and
there's it it's this the baker system
uses the node.js programming language
and so the code that does this is not
even in our project it's like deep down
in the bowels of Baker which is which is
itself an open source code repository on
the LA Times account right deep down
within the code of this like toolkit is
something that knows to look in the
underscore data folder and parse all of
the files right and it's smart enough to
parse comma separated files Json files a
couple other formats and yaml and so
basically Baker's set up to try to make
your life easier right but it sort of
assumes certain things to do that and so
it assumes that if you put a file into
the data folder you want it to be parsed
and you want it to be available to be on
the page and then
the name of the file is then accessible
when you make the template and so like
I'd have to go back in my memory here
but there's a layouts folder that has
all of the HTML templates and you can
see that there's for instance the book
detail page which is what corresponds to
this page on the website about is five
and this page about tulips and chimneys
all four of these pages are made with
the same template
and we see here in this template it's
quite complicated for dumb reasons
because I'm not very good at coding you
can see that it's using templating tags
to kind of print out the title of the
book its description and then that table
of contents right and so that that data
is coming from the underscore data
folder if we look at the poem detail
page
which which makes the which takes the
yamifi makes the poem you can see that
here it's using a sort of little bit of
template code to Loop through each line
of the poem and print it line by line
um it's not just puking the text on the
page because there's some complicated
styles that have to be done to maintain
the Integrity of EE Cummings unusual
typography
um but basically the stuff you're doing
is coming out kind of right here right
and so the poem text which is that
attribute that we see in the yaml file
is being parsed by a custom function
that I've written and then each line in
it is being printed into the template
does that answer your question Sean yeah
thanks yep and there's a whole world
here where these line numbers are used
to manage the custom indentations of EE
Cummings which is quite a lot of fun
um if you really are into CSS there's
some fun ways to contribute this is part
of why I did this project uh like for
instance this poem is sideways which is
actually how it was intended by EE
Cummings and so we had to customize the
CSS just for this page
um my favorite ticket in our issue
tracker currently is about that poem
which is called life hurl my because
it's actually a question of academic
dispute about whether the poem should be
rotated clockwise as it was done in the
first edition or counterclockwise as it
was done in George fermage's
um
George furman's complete poems
um I currently have this ticket being
reviewed by um George Webster who is
America's leading EE Cummings scholar he
believes that counterclockwise is
correct and that because that is how EE
Cummings initially intended it in his
personal notes
um from the archives Scholars who've
been reviewed he's he's going to scan
that for me when he can find he actually
has EE Cummings papers uh and so he will
he will try to scan that for me and we
will resolve the tickets so this is a
fun ticket that's not about code it's
about something silly but anyway
what do you guys this is this and then
you get philosophical which is like well
should our website recreate what the
first edition was
Faithfully or should it recreate what EE
Cummings intention was that was later
restored by Scholars you know 60 70
years later right I think the answer
there is it has to expose all the bits
like if there's a poem with many
different variants the web page can just
keep on scrolling
so you would say I should we should
print it uh rotate it both ways I think
yeah I think the original way first and
then the other way with copious
explanations and
nitpicking about why why about why these
things are I I think the library of
America tries to go with what the author
intended
yeah and that's what the scholars tend
to like so that so I have right here
with me uh there's a there's a guy named
George fermage and so George furmers is
the guy who put together the what's
called complete poems which was is done
by um live right who still exists as a
publisher who published the first
edition and um and his sort of
philosophy in putting the book together
was to restore Cummings intent right but
you could do better than that you can
both have it coming and have all of the
nitpicky academic debates afterwards I
think that's right I'm kind of I I think
we have to have a philosophy for the
site which I have to deal with when I
merge things but I think with I kind of
am leaning towards we go with the intent
once it's resolved and then maybe we
have a footnote that could link to this
ticket or uh I don't know what but it's
it's an interesting question it's an
interesting question so that's that's my
life as a maintainer uh thank you for
indulging me
um and so where we left was we had
Sean's question about the template and
we got that handled and so I think we're
maybe ready to start actually editing
the code so everybody click that first
link in your ticket
and get up
your kind of file which you're going to
edit which should only have the title
and the first line if it has the text
already I've made a mistake and we need
to find you another one just speak up
but
to kind of get back to what Ron was
saying earlier I need to get this in my
other browser hold on
um the traditional way of doing get get
until the last few years was to make a
copy of the repository on your computer
and to use your terminal to sort of
interact with the file right but now
GitHub has some really powerful tools
for making these edits directly in your
browser and since what we're doing is
pretty simple we're going to do that and
get you guys kind of like on the board
um without having to deal with all the
terminal crap and that really awesome
tool is kind of buried within github's
interface like you might not even know
it's there right and what it is is it's
this pencil tool right here in the right
hand side the upper right of the file
viewer you can hit that down arrow I
want everybody to hit that down arrow
and just look at it
and GitHub actually offers two different
ways
to edit your stuff in your browser if
you pick the first option edit this file
you'll get their kind of like Legacy
option that they developed a few years
ago which is very nice right and it's
one way to edit the file in the browser
but below that you can see that there's
a link that says open in github.dev and
this is like the cool new thing that
they are going to gradually replace the
older stuff with that has a lot more
cool features and things to take
advantage of and so I'm going to ask
everybody to hit open in
github.dev in that pull down
Simon you want to explain what this is
yeah this is um so Microsoft have an a
text editor so you can install your
computer called vs code Visual Studio
code and it's one of the best pieces of
software they've released in years it's
completely open source and this is it it
turns out it's written in JavaScript and
it can run in a browser just as well as
it runs on your computer so when you hit
github.dev they're actually launching
effectively the Leading Edge Microsoft
like code editing environment purely in
your browser for you to edit files
directly on GitHub this is a revelation
for me like I never thought I would
spend most more of my time in a browser
writing code than I would doing it on on
like a proper computer but actually no
this is it's such a good editor it's so
convenient you know it's a a click in
the menu to get there but I actually
find myself using this for all kinds of
different projects now
so yeah this is effectively I think this
is best to breed um code editing
experience and it's freely available and
you just click a button and you browser
and off you go yeah and you could do
this on a Chromebook or even on your
phone
um and it makes these tools a lot more
accessible to people too you don't need
a two thousand dollar MacBook you know
which I think is very important
personally
um
um so what I've done is I've opened up
my poem you should see yours and then in
uh chapter six about editing the code I
have a little snippet just to get you
started and this is just intended to be
the like shell of where your text
attribute is going to go you'll notice
that there's this sort of little
configuration bit here on this attribute
that's because unlike the other
um values in our yaml file this is a
multi-line entry right so the poem is
going to go over more than one line of
code and this is just one way of telling
yaml that that's what's going to happen
right and then the negative one tells it
um each line will have one white space
at the start of it that isn't part of
the column that's just there to let you
know that this is one kind of Chunk
right and so you should just paste
something that's like in here and then
below it we just want to start typing
the poem right and so I'm going to
um
I'm going to get to the poem myself but
let me grab the link for my ticket so
back in my ticket I have this other link
right
and I can go to
um
that page
and what I'm going to do is just do a
split screen which you know this is
obviously a matter of taste or whatever
different people like to do things
different ways but I'm going to
um split my screen and I could see here
on the right hand side of this page is
the poem that I need to type
and so I'm just going to type it in and
so this is maybe going to take us all
depending on how long your poem is you
know five to ten minutes and so I just
asked everybody to kind of do their best
to transcribe what they see on the page
okay so I'm just going to shut up for a
minute and do that
and you go ahead and do yours too
if you have any
Adrian what's up
um just just want to confirm the we are
retyping the first line like because
there's the first line attribute and
then but in the text where you want the
first line to start with the first line
that's correct yeah and the first line
attribute is there so that I could make
um
I can make this page on the website
which is a common type of index for
poetry if you've ever seen it you know
yeah I got you just wanted to make sure
yep okay how do I get back to the book
oh so in your ticket run there's a link
the second link in your ticket
um which poem is yours
uh yellow ah
so for instance uh nobody wears a yellow
we can see the link is right here
which I'm gonna try to drop in the chat
and see how I do okay
so Ron there's your link all right
okay I'll just go back to the issue okay
awesome
all right
okay
can you tell that when EE Cummings wrote
these uh typewriters were the cool new
thing
I don't think we would have these poems
if they'd never invented the typewriter
thank you
there's spring the magic word
and you know obviously the punctuation
is inaccurate to uh according to your
copy desk or your sixth grade English
teacher but that is intentional on the
poet's part so we should just try to
um mirror as closely as we can what he's
up to
okay now I'm just going to proof it
still makes me laugh sometimes
these were of course many of these were
intended as a gag EE Cummings was a
goofball especially when he was young
if you're if you don't like the Poetry
you might be interested in his Memoir he
wrote after coming back home from World
War one which recently entered the
public domain and has been republished
by the New York Review of Books
um it's called the enormous room and
it's about being a prisoner of war in
France but he mostly plays it for Laughs
uh and it's sort of a young man sort of
mockingly um
describing his encounter with the
bureaucracy of War
I have proofed mine twice and I'm
somewhat confident in uh my my work
ultimately all submissions will be
proved against the Furbish by yours
truly
see
foreign
I'm going to give everybody two or three
more minutes if you need more time than
that it's totally fine just speak up but
I'm going to say in two or three minutes
we'll we'll uh we'll move on
I have a couple quick questions yes
um one I was wondering if we all should
be using that like pipe minus one
notation or that's particularly just
your poem that you were doing everyone
should put that in there
um because that's because the pipe tells
the yaml that this will be a multi-line
string right that it's going to go oh I
see more than one line of text so it
knows how to parse it and then the
negative one is a configuration option
that tells that there will be one white
space at the start of each row right if
you don't get this perfectly right
that's something we would litigate in
the pull request which we'll see in a
minute right but that's the that's the
intent of how I've configured the yaml
file I admit it's a little Annoying and
in that case we should all we should
also have a white space at the beginning
of each yes each I should have a single
white space and what you'll find in vs
code is that once you start doing that
every time you hit enter it will do it
for you automatically it's sort of a
smart enough to figure that out
my other question was
um I don't know maybe now that I added
this it's not doing anymore but
originally there was a colon in the poem
and the colon seemed to be telling the
code editor that I was
giving some other like yaml yes
configuration yeah so colons are kind of
reserved for use in parsing the ammo
right we see that after each of our guys
I think that if you see I have a colon
in my poem here I think that if it
follows the pipe and the negative one
it'll chill out and be okay with that
once I added the white space in front of
the line then the the text editor
stopped highlighting it so I think that
it's probably that's exactly what
happened I bet right because because you
know even though this is sort of like
Arcane and like who knows what this is
it's sort of giving instructions right
for like this is how you're supposed to
parse me
hey Ben
um quick typographical question that I'm
running into
um now that I realize I do most of my
writing in Google Docs and it it auto
corrects the mdash when I do the two
regular dashes and there are a couple in
my poem and I actually don't know how to
do the empty I don't know if this is I
can Google it I guess really quick but
I'm like kind of like M dashes are
tricky famously you know journalists
love them you know what am I one of my
favorite things
um working at the LA Times is like
getting to like deal with all the old
newspaper technology and I I once found
the coyote computer system the first
computers that were run at the LA Times
and they had a special key just for
mdashes so that's how much journalists
love the mdash that's incredible so
there's different ways to do it on
different operating systems
um you know the easy lazy way is just to
Google it and then copy and paste it
yeah that's what I'm gonna do but since
you've asked you've allowed me to bring
up one of my favorite hobby horses you
guys may tell that I like stupid weird
uh type type things so I think one of
the great failures of Simon and the
Silicon Valley crowd is that they have
abandoned the compose key so the compose
key was once a commonly found uh key on
where the right ALT key is on your
computer or in other common locations on
a keyboard and it was effectively you
would you would type that and then you
would you'd hit that key and then you
would enter a pattern and it would give
you uh more Arcane characters more
quickly and it used it uses a pneumatic
device where you would hit compose key
then say a tick and an A and you would
get the tick over the A and if you did a
tick and an e you get the tick over the
E and if you did compose and three
hyphens you got an mdash right and so
one thing that I've done this is another
pandemic Splurge is I bought myself a
custom keyboard and I put a goddamn
compose key on it and Linux actually
supports a compose key so if you're
smart if you're wise enough to use Linux
uh The Gnome operating system will
support a compose key and you hold your
keyboard up to the web cameras
everything too tight it's going to be
filthy but yeah it's in the right alt
position I've got the custom keycap dude
because the other thing about the
compose key is that it has a beautiful
Unicode symbol that is actually like
super heavy metal guys like this is the
symbol of the compose key like how heavy
metal is that
the circle and square that could be a
tattoo right and in fact it's a t-shirt
on my Etsy shop
right so if you really want to get into
that I like on my Etsy page
there's a compose key t-shirt so long
live the compose key
Silicon Valley you've let us down yet
again
anyway I can't find it now it's there
in that today yeah that would have been
that would have been pretty cool I'm on
a I'm on Ubuntu so maybe I'll I'll um
I'll have it hack it into having my
right right all key I can probably
that's the way to do it I think it's in
the gnome settings
are your keyboard settings maybe
compose key right there see it yeah yeah
there you go okay
cool cool
I learned something new every day
thank you for letting me tell that story
thing I bought during the pandemic is
that tool to remove keycaps like this is
the special tool that's just for pulling
out keycaps I'm I should not admit this
but I did buy that
all right so has everybody gotten their
poem in I know some of them are longer
than others
what's that
I know you love EE Cummings but he's
driving my copy editor heart crazy he
would have loved that Ron
especially when he was young he got kind
of grumpy when he got old if you ever
read about him he was the kind of
classic modernist really you know these
are young bright
um people who were kind of damaged by
the war and that's what a lot of their
art is about you know Ezra pound or
Gertrude Stein or Ernest Hemingway would
be other examples
and uh Cummings is one who unlike a lot
of the more liberal Greenwich Village
types
um became uh anti-communist where many
of them became pro-communist and so the
1930s for a lot of these uh literary
characters at the time were really a
conflict between Warren camps and their
position toward the Soviet Union
Cummings made a trip to the Soviet Union
which he also wrote about and became a
pretty uh virulent uh anti-soviet
uh anyway
foreign
so we got it in
love it all right so now that we have it
in we have this in the text editor but
like how do we get this back into the
actual repository right and so this is
where if you're on your terminal you
would have to save the file and type
these insane git commands that like tell
it how to do that but because github.dev
is so great we can now do that stuff
just by clicking a couple buttons right
and you can see here on the left hand
side of my text editor we have a little
icon that kind of looks like a tree
right or like a branch coming off with
dots and lines and it's got a blue
circle on it right and that's like a
little notification thing and this is
the commit dialogue or the source
control dialog which allows you to log
your changes that you're making to the
code and so this is another like techie
concept of code repositories is that
every time you make a change into the
Version Control System you have to make
a log entry you have to say I'm going to
change these lines of code right and
that's going to be stored as like a
little transaction and then then also
you typically will if you're doing a
good job you'll provide a description of
what you've done and then that
description is stored along with the
change and that little bundle of
information or that transaction is
called a commit or a code commit right
and
um and so what you typically do is is
you after you make a change you then
write a message and then log it with the
code commit and the way you can do that
in vs code or GitHub Dev is by clicking
that little tree button right so you get
that thing you can see here it even
provides a list of the changes you've
made and if I clicked on it I get What's
called the diff right so it's showing
here on the left here's what the file
looked like before you made the change
here's the diff or the change that you
made on the right so you can look at
that it's often a good idea to do this
before you commit because you might
accidentally change more than one file I
do that like every day right or you
might have changed something made a typo
that you didn't intend and this can
really highlight that change right so I
see here no I think I I pretty much got
what I want I'm feeling good about my
diff
and so then then the final thing to do
is to then go to this text box in the
upper left and to write that line to
describe what you were doing right and
so I'm gonna and like this is always
this sort of creative challenge like
what did I do you know what I mean and
it's a good thought exercise to see if
you can really summarize it in this case
it's really just gonna I'm gonna say I
entered the name of this poem so I'm
just going to copy and paste that so I
entered this guy
and that would be enough I think to have
a good code commit message but there's
an extra piece of sugar that you could
do on GitHub which is you can link your
code commit to the issue that you're
talking about so that those two things
are joined together on the website and
the way you do that
and I'd encourage you all to do this is
you then go back to the issue and I
almost always have to go back and look
because I can't remember but if I go
back and look I can see reasoned
irrefutable unastonished was ticket
number 190. do you see that up there
so that's the number of my ticket and so
then over here in the editor I'm going
to say
fixes hash 190 and you see it's even
Auto completing for me right because
it's connected to GitHub pretty cool
right and so then I'm going to say fixes
number 190 fix is this kind of a magic
word
which tells GitHub that if this code
commit is accepted into the repository
you can close the ticket automatically a
human doesn't even have to go to close
it it'll do it for you it's kind of nice
right you don't have to you could just
put the number and that would still make
the link right but I think this will fix
the ticket so I'm just going to put
fixes
and then so everybody do that put in
your description and try to tag your
issue and then hit this blue button
commit and push
okay then you're going to get this
pop-up and we're going to wait for a
second and then I'll explain what this
pop-up is but I'm going to give
everybody a chance just to write their
message and hit the button
and it's like
sorry Ben can you just explain how so
I've got my my tech uh the yaml file
there so if I how do I find uh how to
commit it's a little tricky at first
because it's it's part of the odd
interface of the text editor but do you
see on the left hand side there's a
black bar that's up against the edge of
the window
yeah the fourth icon down does it have
like a little blue little blue pop-up
yeah so that click that icon and that's
that's the source control Tab and so
that's a tab within vs code that
actually this is what makes vs code so
popular is that the text editor is
actually integrated with the version
control system for you and so you can
use it to make changes to code without
having to go into your terminal or to
talk to git and GitHub it will do it on
your behalf right and so by clicking
that you then get a new
um box should open up from the left and
then in that upper left text box that's
where you type your your commit message
and then hit the blue button
yep and you'll get to this pop-up and
then we'll deal with that in a second
everybody okay anybody stuck
okay I I didn't get to a pop-up I'm just
getting kind of a loading
animation I don't know maybe I need to
when you hit commit and push yeah
you might try clicking it again that's
probably a web connection bug would be
my guess you know because all this is
happening over the internet
I'm I'm getting a similar thing but what
happened is a little window popped up
that I'm supposed to type a name of a
branch into that's what's going to come
next after this so did you already hit
the fork repository button no I just
clicked commit and push and it went
right to that
um well for some reason you didn't get
this pop-up but you're on the next step
and so if you're on the next step you're
okay right so basically just to return
to kind of one of our initial principles
we can't commit our code directly to my
repository or you can't because you
don't have authority right I can't let
anybody change my code and so how do you
get around that well the way GitHub does
does it is it has you create a copy of
my repository that you own and that
you're allowed to do whatever you want
with right and that's called a fork
right so a fork is your personal copy of
somebody else's code and because it's
open source you can do whatever you want
within certain limits but you can't
change the website right because it's my
version of the code that's connected to
the website through a whole other set of
technology and so the forks are the the
sort of um standard GitHub way of
managing uh making changes to code and
then proposing they'd be accepted back
in the original repository it's just
like a little cycle right you edit the
code you save it in your fork and then
the pull request is asking the owner of
the original to accept the change that
lives in your fork right but because
this is your first commit you don't have
a fork yet right and so an initial step
that GitHub is going to take here is
it's going to say well you're trying to
make changes I'm reading right from the
box now right you're trying to make
changes to a project you don't have
right access to AKA you can't write to
the repository right do you want to
create a fork in this project to commit
your proposed changes and my answer is
yes so I'm going to hit the blue button
everybody else should hit the blue
button too
and then that's going to go about
creating a fork and and this is where it
starts to get a little Arcane but you
can see at the very top here there's a
pop-up box right and it's basically
asking you to create a branch on your
fork So within repositories there could
be different copies of the code that
sort of break off from each other so
let's say you own the repository and you
want to work on a feature but you you
don't want to have that go live as
you're working on it you want to be able
to make commits and then after a certain
amount of time send that back into the
main line of code you do that by what's
making called a branch right and a
branch is really like a mini Fork it's
like a fork that's within the repository
right rather than like a whole separate
repository and this is a little
confusing but basically you know when
you have right access to a repository
you traditionally create branches
that that you'll then send back for a
merge and so github's default behavior
is when you make a commit is to say well
you want to branch that off where you
want to Branch it and they just see that
as sort of a hygienic and kind of
professional default setting so that
people aren't just like ramming code
into their Master Branch without
thinking about it too much right it's a
little Annoying it might not be
necessary in this case and um but this
is how it's set up and so here's the
thing the the reason it's so useful here
is that a pull request is actually about
um the changes in my Branch here are the
ones that I'm proposing so it is good
practice if you're working on lots of
different things that will be pull
requests you want each of those things
to be in a different branch so yeah it's
a bit of a weird esoteric thing but for
this particular
um exercise that we're doing here it's
actually it's a really useful default
yeah and so some people will get serious
about their Branch names and they might
put the ticket number in the branch name
or a descriptive thing but in our case
we're just going to accept the default
which is patch one because it's your
first patch another piece of jargon a
patch is really just like code that you
want to change right here's the change
that's the patch right and so I'm just
going to click into that box and as the
instructions say I'm going to hit enter
right and then it's going to say hey
you've committed changes to your fork do
you want to switch to your fork and
continue making changes say yes I want
to switch to my Fork
I can't imagine what would happen if you
said no to that I think things would get
very confusing yeah and so now we've
moved over to the editor has now moved
and you can see that the URL if you look
at it carefully is no longer pale wire
me slash cummings.e it's first PR
cummings.e because that's the name of my
user and so you're probably going to see
your username in this spot in the URL as
well
did that work for everyone
cool so now back on GitHub you have your
own copy of the repository that's been
created and to make our pull requests we
need to go there and interact with it
and so this is a little clunky as well
but if you hit the menu box in the the
menu line the three lines at the LA
times we call this the hamburger if you
hit the uh the hamburger icon in the
upper left you can see that there's a
link at the bottom called go to
repository does everybody see that
oh
go ahead and hit that guy and then in
another tab it's just we're going to be
right back at a repo but we'll see in
the upper left hand corner it's it's got
the Little Fork icon and it's first PR
now right and it says below forked from
pale wire and so this is a copy of
repository that you now own and have
right access to that contains the branch
patch one that has your poem right and
so in your repo the poem has been
entered but since it's not in the
original Repository
it's uh it's not on the site yet and so
this is kind of the final step of your
like secular your journey is to then say
I'm gonna propose to the maintainer of
the original repository to accept my
patch as a pull request how about all
that jargon right and you can see that
GitHub knows this is what people do and
so they've even put a little pop-up
yellow box at the top where they're
saying hey somebody pushed to this patch
just one minute ago
would you want to compare and make a
pull request out of that with this big
green button
it's like that is in fact exactly what I
want to do right and there's other
buttons and other ways to do this in the
interface but they just know this is
really common so they've put this pop-up
there right and so everybody should go
ahead and click that green button which
is compare and pull request
and then you get to one final form and
so this is the pull request form this is
where you the outside contributor are
going to propose your changes to the
maintainer you can see there's a little
pull down here that says the base
repository pailwire slash EE Cummings
and it's Master branch is being kind of
asked to accept a patch from the head
repository that's you another terrible
piece of jargon and that repository is
first PR and it's coming from its patch
one branch right and if I scroll down
the page you'll see there's the diff
right it's going to say this is the
change that's being proposed to be
included and in between there's like a
little text box and another space to
write and this box is really the place
where you kind of make your case right
so this is going to go in as a sort of
ticket for the maintainer with your code
as a proposal for inclusion and what you
put here is really um can vary but you
know if you you know if your work if
you're if you're making your first ever
contribution or if you're doing
something complicated or whatever you
know you have to realize you have to
convince the person who runs the
repository to accept your change right
and so this this form is often a place
where people try to be persuasive you
know they'll say hey there's this bug
you can see the bug in ticket number
whatever and I researched it and I found
out that this was the problem and then I
figured out here's how we're going to
fix it I made the change to fix it and
here it is what do you think right and
so like that type of rhetoric is really
common and then you'll see it in a
second the maintainer's job is to sort
of review your proposal and try to
responsibly decide whether to integrate
your code whether to ask for you to make
some changes to it or whether to reject
your proposal right and these this sort
of interaction that happens is often
done between total strangers
um on other sides of the planet one of
my favorite things in life is to wake up
in the morning and like someone in
Ukraine or Japan and has sent me a pull
request it's just incredible you know
um
and it honestly blows my mind every time
it happens but um
but that there's there's tens of
thousands of these little interactions
happening all around the world every day
via GitHub and so this will be your kind
of first shot at that
um uh because this is something we're
doing in a controlled environment
together and the change we're making is
pretty clear I think that just us saying
explicitly what we're doing which is
entering a poem and tagging the ticket
that those two things are probably uh
kind of good enough to have a good pull
request here but I think usually I mean
Simon is more of a maintainer than I am
usually you're looking for maybe a
little more than that Simon or what do
you look for in in with this message I
mean the big thing is the worst thing
that can happen is somebody shows up
with a 100 line pull request for
something that you didn't know they were
going to do and that and now you have to
read through the account you don't
understand the background so the link to
the issue is crucial for me because I
always want things to be discussed in an
issue before they get to the point where
people are submitting code and then
honestly I used to write really long
descriptions in these until I realized
that a better thing to do with that is
to have documentation that's in the
repository which you update as part of
the pull request so for my projects I
tend to encourage people to have a pull
request which has tests and
documentation and the implementation and
then you can have a sentence and I don't
care but for projects that don't have
documentation or what but you end up
wanting wanting a bit more detail than
that
um something which we can demonstrate
actually with one of the pull requests I
just filed is that you can file a pull
request and then add your own comments
to it so you can actually get away with
a sort of very short initial thing but
then start a conversation in a thread
and Link that into the into the into the
code itself if you want to to detail
more about how you approach something
great tips so once you've kind of got
your initial message together you just
hit this green button here which says
create pull request and so I would ask
everybody to do that
and you can see that now we're at the
page that looks a lot like an issue but
unlike an issue it has a file change
attached to it right that's the major
difference that's what makes it the pull
request
and you can actually see here at the top
of the repository in the pull request
tab
or if you click there are all the pull
requests that have come in and just in
the last few minutes everybody's pull
requests are landing right we can see
there actually were two ongoing
discussions with uh two of our heroic
contributors here at the bottom that I
haven't resolved yet and then here's all
the transcriptions that we've been doing
here in class right and if it's one of
my two ones they've got a little bit of
extra commentary in them which might be
interesting to see excellent let me find
one here so here's Simon's first one so
I'm now looking at this as me or you
know as the first PR user who is
effectively Simon's peer right like
another outside contributor and so Simon
has done his little comments oh look at
that so you want to explain it
uh yes so um I hit the M Dash issue
um so I decided to put a comment around
this and then add a little screenshot of
the original so you can see I am as a
wind I've got my mdash there in the in
the in the in the um origin it looked
like that just so that we can have a
conversation about whether or not that's
the right typographical approach for
rendering this poem yep and in a long
pull request where a bunch of code gets
changed you could have multiple threads
like this you can talk about this line
or that line and they can kind of Branch
off into like a more targeted
discussions so so to someone like my
fake user this is a discussion that
they're allowed to join right but they
don't really have the authority to do
anything with the code right but if I
change browser tabs now and I go back to
the browser tab where I'm me the
maintainer of it
and I go to that same pull request
you'll see a slightly different
interface you'll see at the bottom that
there's now a big green button that says
merge pull request and if I hit that it
will accept Simon's changes into the
Repository
right but being part of you know one
when I look at it it's the first thing
I'll do I'll read what they have and
then I hit this tab right here file
changed and this will show me the
changes right and so to me as a you know
responsible maintainer I always want to
just carefully walk through the changes
make sure I understand everything that's
happening and then I'm allowed to make
comments that are part of a code review
that can happen through the GitHub
interface where I could say well I could
ask Simon a question why did we do this
or I could suggest the change what's
like that this is okay but what if we we
could save two lines of code if we wrote
it this other way right or this looks
like maybe a bug you know and like and
that that conversation can happen
through this process so in our case here
today whoa my desk is going down
um
my standing desk just rebelled so uh
so in my case here today the review for
this repository is not really code
review right it's a text review and so I
have firmages first edition and so I'm
going to go to the index of this and I'm
going to look up Simon's poem which is
supposing I dreamed this right which is
on page 311.
so I'm going to thumb to that and then
I'm gonna just proof his key punching
against uh what I find in firmages
Edition and that also gets us both the
first edition and firmage which is kind
of what I'm going for right
and so um
should we have a poetry reading uh
supposing I dreamed this only imagine oh
I see the first thing so we see here
this is actually a sort of there's no
way Simon would have known this but in
many of the first editions of Cummings
there are spaces put after the commas
and the poems but the scholars have
found that in his original intention in
his archives he omits those right and so
this is a case where there's probably a
discrepancy between the first edition
and fermage but our policy as a site is
to exclude those spaces and so this
would be a case where I could make the
change myself or I could suggest the
changed to Simon I think there even is a
suggestion option right Simon's that's
directly I think because you're the
owner of the repository that's allowed
to I definitely could but I'm gonna do
like the starter review and so now I've
just made a kind of suggestion right
that we're gonna change remove that
space only imagine when Dave has
thrilled day has thrilled I like that
you are a house around which I am a wind
your walls will not reckon how strangely
my life is curved since the best he can
do is to peer and then
peer through windows on observe this is
another case where we want uh to take
the space out
and so then I'm going to add another
comment there
right uh through space unobserved m Dash
looks good Simon nice
and then here's another one where we
want to take the space out
add the review comment
listen for out of all things and then
there's no space after the parenthesis
this is another change
right
uh dream is no one's fool
I love the curly quote there Simon well
done
semicolon
if this wind who I am prowls carefully
around this house of you
love being so Simon's got there I'm like
thumbs up so I can resolve that and say
good job Simon and then that one closes
right
love being such and so here we have
another white space thing
so I'm going to hit the suggestion
button and just make that little change
such or such the normal corners of your
heart will never guess how much my
wonderful jealousy is dark if light
should flower oh you have a semicolon
and in firmage it's a colon
huh
uh we could look back at the first
edition I'm not you know it's pretty
hard to read that scan sometimes
or laughing Sparkle from the shut house
around and around which a poor wind will
roam okay so that's the poem with these
minor changes I would be okay with
including it so I've made my suggestions
to Simon and then I'm going to hit
finish review
and I can hit a button here called
request changes and so then this is
going to be a volley that I send back to
him the contributor I'm going to say uh
you know and then I can send a message
that will go back to him so I can say
contribution looks great generally
and this is where again being polite is
always uh you know a good approach
especially if you're dealing with people
you don't know contribution looks great
generally thank you for doing this you
know I'll play acting a little here
there are a few and then explaining why
I want to make the changes there are a
few small inconsistencies
between the first editions spacing and
what we see in firmages
um
complete poems
which is our authoritative
Source I've made those changes here
those edits here once they're accepted
um we can merge this request right so
that's my little note back to Simon I
have options here to either just send a
general comment to sort of do a thumbs
up and approve it because sometimes
multiple people approve things before
they go out and then finally there's one
that's called request changes which is
maybe the most common where you're
saying look here's what I want you to do
right and so I hit submit review and
that is a code review if you've ever
heard that term we just did it and we
could see that back on the pull request
there my comment appears with this code
form for Simon because I use the
suggestion panel
um he's actually able to accept my
suggestions with new commits simply by
um hitting the little pull down in these
conversations this is an incredible
GitHub feature a great example of just
making things easier through user
interface so Simon I'm just going to go
ahead and accept these just to show how
it works
oh
I've accepted some of them already this
might as a suggestion Collision let's
see what happens
um I'll do the last two here don't worry
about it I'd suggest doing a merged
emerge a squash merger on this one
because otherwise we'll end it with a
ugly set of times yeah that's fine so
we've done this and the changes are
there and so now if I go back to files
changes
and I look we could see that those white
spaces are gone right they've been fixed
I'm feeling good about the poem
could always be something else goes
wrong
but I see the change requested shows up
I'm not feeling good about it
and so um
I think there's a way I can then accept
the changes right so like back here I do
in the interface I say yep I'm good with
it now approve
and now you can see my approval shows up
everything's run through and I have this
big green button to merge the pull
request uh Simon was saying I should
squash it which basically means combine
everything into a single commit so that
all our little changes don't go into the
log which is you know
more of a aesthetic thing but I think
the correct decision and so I'm just
going to say let's squash it
they all get put together into one uh
commit message
and I hit that button
and now it says you know pale wire
merged this commit into master
and if we look at the commit log for the
repository which we see right here we
now see in the the most recent commit
message is Simon right and so he's now I
think for the first time an author on
this repository and the change from his
Fork has been integrated into the main
branch
congratulations Simon thank you for
doing it his ticket was number 181 if I
go back to that ticket
oh that's the pull work this ticket it
should close automatically but sometimes
that takes a minute
um just because GitHub has like a
process that has to play out
um he maybe didn't say fixes in his
message and so I'm just going to go
ahead and close this issue manually
because that poem has been entered and
so I think we're good to go right
um
we have on our page now 14 pull requests
which is so exciting for me thank you
guys for putting these in this is
awesome
um once class is over I'm gonna go
through and review all of these and get
everybody's poem in by I hope the end of
the day uh if there's any small stuff I
might just clean it up myself or you
know send it back for commit comments in
case anybody has any issues um one final
thing I want to show you is that because
of how this repository is set up when
you make a code commit it automatically
republishes the website and that's via
another great GitHub feature which is
called actions and so actions which is
another tab at the top is effectively a
cloud computing platform dedicated just
to your repository this is a truly
incredible feature of GitHub so
basically you're able to take events
that occur within your repository or
schedule tasks that you set up yourself
and you're able to run your code in the
cloud for free if your site is open
source which is just ah it's like the
greatest thing going in open source
software if you ask me and what I've
done if you read the the code repository
is I've configured this repository with
an action that uses the baker Frameworks
tools to republish the website every
time there's a Code commit and so we can
see here that two minutes ago when we
merged Simon's code it rebuilt and
republished the website and so Simon's
poem was
um
supposing I dreamed this right Simon and
so now this is the big drum roll please
if I go to cummings.ee and I go to the
is five and I go to supposing I dream
this look it's now a hyperlink right
when before it wasn't and if I click in
there's Simon's work now transcribe and
available on the web we hope you know
forever or at least until the end of you
know the internet and I'm available in
Google search also available
automatically as a CSV or Json output if
anybody wants to create an EE Cummings
bot I will work with you I would love to
see that happen but everything is
machine readable on the site my dream is
to do more with that one of my friends
has said we just have to name it deep
fakes with two Capital E's and I think
uh I think well that's my only request
um so we'll get everybody else in but
that's effectively the whole cycle and
the end of the Spiel you know if you
were to if you were to enter more than
one poem you know you could just repeat
that over and over again to enter each
poem sometimes people will submit
multiple poems at the same time this is
like a a matter of art with pull
requests which is do you just do one
thing or do you try to do multiple
things to save time
um I think Simon and I are probably on
that one thing at a time kind of train
just because that makes the life of the
maintainer easier and the code is more
easily kind of managed but honestly
that's all a matter of kind of art you
know what I mean and approach so I mean
with that we've really reached the end
of the tutorial and and what you need to
see on my screen but I'd like to leave
some time now just to um answer your
questions and just have a uh you know
talk about anything you want to talk
about related to pull requests or open
source software or GitHub or modernist
poetry if you want to continue to
indulge me
so
what do you guys want to know
got a quick question I was curious so
when I was doing my poem
for this specific
against I couldn't read some
because of the the scam yeah so is there
like I don't know sort of a standardized
way or something for me to bring that to
you in this case your attention that
look I'm trying to submit something I
know isn't done or right but it's most
of the work
um so this is uh with the example we
showed with my pull request this is I
like using the comments on lines feature
so you can put in the poem submit the
pull request and then you can add your
own comments to the pull request saying
these three lines here I don't think are
quite right so I did that by adding in a
little screenshot you don't even need to
do that and yeah that's um something
that I think is really important is it's
okay to talk to yourself in GitHub
issues and GitHub bull requests I have a
lot of repositories with issue threads
with dozens of comments they're all just
me talking back and forth and recording
the decisions I was making and asking
myself questions that I resolved later
on that these things are free there's no
size limits on them there's no there's
no reason not to add information and
questions like that and I think raising
it as a discussion item is definitely
the way to go you know because it you
know who knows who's maintaining the
repo and if you don't know them you can
get differing results but I think most
maintainers want people to be
transparent to like ask their questions
and just to like raise problems most
people that's what most maintainers want
obviously there are jerks on the
internet you know what I mean and so it
happens every once in a while you will
have what we call nerd tosterone yeah
before I work that'll come up in these
conversations but I think you should err
on the side of just clear communication
and so like in the case of this repo I
would want just like what Simon proposed
or even somebody just filing an issue
like honestly I am fine with people
filing issues that are just questions
like what do I do and then we just have
the conversation and the issue it can
almost be like a helpline because I
would rather have that conversation than
the person not contribute you know
um and I want to know about the problems
in this case the particular thingy thing
is we already have a policy which is we
go to the firmage right and that's based
on my reporting where basically I
developed a little Cadre of ee coming
Scholars who I interviewed and I got
their advice and they were like if it's
ever weird just use the firmage and so
that's kind of our policy and there
actually is a file in the repo called
the contributing file which you'll see
on a lot of repos where I've kind of
laid out the rules of the repo I didn't
show that today but in there you can
find the explanation of the yaml the
links to the first position and some
answers to kind of an FAQ about issues
like this and in there it just says we
go to the firmage which has its own
problems but it's you know better than
not knowing we could always go back to
the library and just like look at it
[Laughter]
but they actually have more than one
first edition at Central Library they've
been rebound by the library about 50
years ago
prior to the fire so they survived the
fire
um which there's a whole book about
Susan Orleans wrote called the library
book it's about the LA Library fire
excellent book
and the history of Los Angeles as well
um do you mind if I just ask a
clarifying question there so in terms of
like Simon your workflow there where
you're saying your commenting so if I'm
on
where my pull request is in GitHub
I've just got this Branch there's no
conflicts with Brett based branch and
then I've got the option to leave
comment below is that where you're
having that conversation or are you
opening up
the two places I'll have I'll often if
that's an issue I tend to prefer using
the issue for the comments once I've
opened a pull request I'll use comments
on the pull request and I just find that
they're both places where people see you
can add comments to individual commits
but I don't feel like that sounds good a
place just because people can miss them
there like this everyone involved in the
repository is going to be reading
everything on the issues and everything
on the pull request that's the safest
place to put this stuff
thank you
other questions
um Ben I couldn't help but um notice you
you mentioned this is actually kind of
like more of a baker related question
um I was playing around with your um
first visual story
um setup
um and it was really really well done
and I was actually trying to hack it to
redesign like my personal site because I
know it's mainly made to be just like a
one-page kind of thing but I I'm
assuming in Baker you're able to like
make a somewhat more not super robust
website but something that has a couple
of you know oh you have different pages
um is that something that's appropriate
because I never know I've never this is
I've never actually submitted a pull
request to an open source
um project and I know obviously
different maintainers have their
different kind of like General like uh
what's accepted and what's not uh from
what you said is like is submitting just
kind of an issue even though it's not an
issue but just like hey is there a Best
practice of how to make a website
because I want to know from my users
what the problem is and so if they want
to email me that's fine if they want to
file an issue that's fine because I I
often think it's better if it's an issue
because then future other people could
Google it and see a conversation totally
sounds like in this case it may be like
a documentation bug you know what I mean
there might be a way to strengthen the
documentation so to answer the question
basically every HTML file you make in
the baker project will be served and so
you could just make a file called
foo.html and then there'd be slash Foo
on your site and so you can add hoc make
as many pages as you want which may not
be documented well enough now that I
think about it right it was really much
more like I like like connecting them
kind of before because like my and it's
really just my lack of general I'm not
not a web developer kind of thing but it
was a desire of mine because I was like
oh I really like this framework because
you know I really was originally using
um looking at some of the other ones and
I was kind of like oh wow this is really
cool so
um yeah the feature I'd point you to
that's really powerful is you can
dynamically generate pages right that
was that was kind of my Hope was that
like for like a Blog that I might have
on my personal site exactly it would
dynamically generate so for instance
Baker does the LA Times coronavirus
tracker which has a page for each of
California's 58 counties but there's
only one template right and then there's
there's a little bit of JavaScript
that's in the configuration file that
tells it to to generate one for each um
one for each County that I think is
better documented but yeah sure could be
improved so if you really wanted to be
like the a plus plus student that the
maintainers love
is if you figured it out you would
submit the readme edit that like that's
missing like if you if you really want
to make friends like that stuff like
that people love I do yeah all the time
typos anytime you see a typo in any
documentation you can submit a pull
request but also I love adding examples
because everyone who writes
documentation always forgets that people
just want to see an example of the thing
yeah if you find something's missing
example you submit an example there's a
good chance it'll be accepted
yeah and you might not hear back from
them for months who knows if they're
paying attention or whatever but it's
still it's a nice thing to do
totally
I think you just commented on a question
that that I had as tied to this because
you guys said that you know one pull
request at a time is uh you know better
handleable or whatever but so if I did
if I was looking at the doctor reading
documentation or something and I saw a
typo like how small of a thing is worthy
of a pulled requester
totally worth it I I accept pull
requests like that all the time I love
them and I do those too just being a
news person you get kind of uptight
about that stuff you know what I mean
and so like if if honestly we just went
through the class right we just went
through that class so that class we just
did is a repo on GitHub right and so did
you guys spot any typos I'm sure they're
in there did anybody you know if you saw
one we could do a pull request right now
I would you know or if like did I get a
link wrong you know I'm sure I screwed
something up I think I was I wrote that
with three beers on Wednesday night so
like I'm sure something is wrong right
and uh
um and so that would be a case where
yeah I've actually had people do that on
other classes and I really appreciate it
you know I think it's great
sometimes it's embarrassing to see all
your typos but you get over that
thanks yeah
I'd misspelled persuasive I saw that
this morning
duh
you could write a bot that just found
typos on GitHub couldn't you
people have done it
yeah
I actually I there are companies that do
bots that like run the automatic
analysis and then spam repos with pull
requests suggesting fixes and they tend
to get bams like people they're they're
limits to what people will put out if it
was a security flaw that's one thing but
like yeah
other questions
um then I have to have to bounce in a
bit but um I um just wanted to ask you
so you're you're going to be at night
car next year yes I will be in Nashville
that's what we were talking about
earlier so folks who don't know our data
journalism World which is kind of where
I was nurtured and uh brought into
adulthood uh uh allegedly
um is uh has an annual conference which
is called the night car conference and
it's in a different city every year and
so it's it's where the data journalists
of the world kind of convene classes
like this it's what I love about it is
it's really a Hands-On event it's a
place where people teach each other code
and teach each other data analysis and
teach each other how to file public
records requests for valuable government
databases and like all this kind of the
place where journalism and Technology
meets is at this conference and it's
really focused on skills building and so
um I have a little dog and pony show of
these kind of first classes where I have
five or six of them and and so we'll do
a couple at night car we're going to do
the the one I do the most which is
called first python notebook which is
really teaching people data analysis
with the Jupiter notebook which Simon
has helped with in the past
and um
and I want to do first visual story but
I haven't heard back yet but um um you
know we have a few other ones there's
one so if you go to my website which is
palewire
um you can find them in the
documentation page uh there's ones for
GitHub actions and uh uh Django admin
panels and a couple other things
um yeah I'm bummed I'm gonna be in a
wedding in India and I'm gonna miss oh
wow um yeah wedding in India though yes
you can't miss that you're very excited
it's incredible yeah I'm very excited it
happens to be like the literal weekend
that it's that it's happening so which
city whereabouts in India it's going to
be in Agra
um which of course has the the Taj Mahal
but some friends and I are going to be
hanging around um in Delhi beforehand
and yeah we're making a whole making a
whole ordeal out of it one of my first
friends from college to kind of get
hitched so
um oh that's awesome I've never been to
India but I've always wanted to go I'm
so tempted to just you know bring my
computer and join virtually but my worst
demons you know I'm gonna lift that up
they're all the other years but if you
you said you've never been in Nashville
like uh this isn't related to this class
at all but you gotta you gotta try the
hot chicken if you're uh if you're a um
a spicy food it's definitely taken over
Los Angeles it's colonized Our Fair yeah
yeah I should get the real thing right
no I mean if you get the off authentic
one I I mean I'm not a spicy food person
but it really it was it was a different
dimension that's the hot ones kind of
special almost you get that whole
experience yeah I gotta do that you're
right I got it that's going on the list
um but yeah Simon Ben thank you so much
I I always appreciate uh both of you
guys putting these these things on and
they're super helpful and uh so yeah
thank you for coming
thank you I'm glad I'm glad it's helpful
totally all right have a good day guys
yep you too
um anything else folks want to talk
about no pressure or anything but you
know my wife's out of town I got nothing
to do
did I just confirm what actually
happened with in terms of so I had a
fork of your repo are the main changes
to that my Fork yes and then what kind
of I just get in my head around what
actually happened when I'm creating that
pool request and what goes what kind of
happens there if that makes sense to
then
for it then to turn up in the original
repo I'm just trying to get my head
around no I understand that does that
make sense so I don't know if I'm
explaining myself
thank you
so if
I mean I guess one way to think about
this is nothing changes at all until the
pull request is approved you know you've
got your changes in your in your
repository your the pull request is
almost a sort of transient sort of um
it's you've started that conversation
you've said said to Ben here are the
changes I would like to make
um
and nothing will happen then we can have
a conversation around this thing and so
forth but until he hits that big green
button there are no changes made to your
repository or to his repository when he
hits the green button his repository
gets updated again your repository stays
alone and you could leave it there for
the rest of the time and it'll sit there
as a sort of
Frozen version of the thing that you
were working on
um but so really the um the Magic Moment
is the it's the merge it's when those
changes that you've suggested emerged
into into Ben's repository that um and
and added and published the website yeah
and so I've shared my screen again so I
think this is one you entered right and
so we could see that this green
highlighted thing that's the patch that
you're nominating for inclusion and so
what closes the circle is that is sent
back across to the original right and
then I'm asked to merge it into mine and
so basically your changes would be
integrated right and so before so GitHub
is really the reason it's worth so much
money and it's done so well is it just
makes like buttons and forms to make
that easier right right but underneath
the hood if I put a dot diff at the end
of the URL we see actually the code that
goes to the computer and so this is the
patch or what used to be called the the
diff for GitHub and things like GitHub
this this was all done over email you'd
have a mailing list and people would be
emailing each other literally these
decks would be sent via email and it was
horrible it was such a difficult process
for everyone involved because you have
to manage your email inbox and apply
these changes one by one and review them
locally and so forth and GitHub made all
of that so much smoother like the amount
of value it added to open source in
general just for making the stuff not be
a horrifically like painful email-based
process was enormous
yeah
the shoe so I think it's just because I
suppose I'm thinking of just using the
command line and when you do that the
process is a little bit different so
from what I've seen here kind of
there's a bit of magic going on there so
I'm just trying to get my head around
how that kind of how would relate to
maybe
if I had my own Fork locally so if the
changes landline the way that tends to
work is that it's you you do it all on
your own computer you make your
strangers but then you push them to
GitHub and then you go and click the
buttons on the web interface as well so
once you get to the pull request bit
that's where you're sort of moving away
from what you're doing the command line
and moving into the things that you
exclusively go and get about there
that's right and so I think like support
and the so the pull request really is a
GitHub thing not a git thing you know
what I mean when you really like get
into it it's kind of like a branded
thing that they invented yeah you know
and it's terrible name okay it is I I
still don't know why they called it a
pull request but it's it's a it's been a
revelation in in software um just
generally like the amount of
productivity it's unlocked if it was
called a merge request I think I would
be happier but like it might make sense
yeah my like rant on Version Control is
it's just the number of mixed metaphors
in Version Control is just incredible
like is it a tree like is it a mass
master and a slave is it uh you know
what I mean is it you know what is a
pull and a push like how do those how do
you pull the tree you know it's like
yeah and they they used to call the the
main or Master Branch the trunk do you
remember which is why it's called a
branch right
but then they stop calling it the trunk
and see like oh why are we still calling
it a branch and like it's the whole
thing is a mess like they just need to
pick one metaphor and make it work but
that'll never happen of course because
it's open source software so we're just
lucky it's not full of like misogynist
jokes or something but well the
misogynist checks have been filtered out
over time over time yeah exactly it took
it it only took 30 years so
um the get the the default branch and
get was called Master until a couple of
years ago and it was a huge like
industry-wide effort to switch that
default to be called main instead
um which was and it worked to be I think
it's really impressive but it's it's
it's right but if you look at my
Cummings repo it's still the master
Branch because I made it before that
whole change happened and like I haven't
spent the 30 minutes it would take to
make that change which I probably should
do it's just like one of those things I
haven't got to you know
is there a way to
update my Fork
to match the master again or do I have
to great question
there is that's called fetching Upstream
so this is another metaphor it's a river
metaphor right which is that your code
is is uh Downstream of the the trunk
right and so when changes are being made
to what you forked from you might want
to catch up at some point right and so
that's that scene is going to the
Upstream origin right and so there's a
so in github's language they call that
fetching upstream and you can do it from
the command line by by like with a
couple command line tricks but then
there's also a way to I have to look it
up every single time I do it I've been
doing this stuff for like 15 years I
can't remember how to fetch from
Upstream when I have to go and Google
for it every single time
it is a pain and so GitHub interface you
can see my screen
they have a little button here for this
which is uh sync Fork
right and that'll let you do that and
then there's this this also this is the
pull request button that isn't the
pop-up and so they kind of hide that
stuff in here
and so like a cycle would be let's say I
want to contribute like something later
is I would go back to my main branch I
would fetch Upstream to make sure I've
caught up I would then make a new Branch
where my new SEC pull request number two
is going to go and then I would submit
that right the only time you have an
issue there is like well if your changes
conflict with something that's Upstream
let's say in the in the in between
period right you've edited a file that
changed Upstream right and then when you
fetch you get the most infamous hell of
git which is a merge conflict which is
well you change something that somebody
else changed and which one do we keep
right and there's like a whole process
for dealing with that and slaying your
first like conflict message is like part
of your um your rite of passage is like
a as a computer programmer
it's a river metaphor and then why is it
called origin
that's just like CIS admin talk right
anyway
other questions
all right well thanks again everybody I
really appreciate your contributions
um I'm gonna go get something to eat my
wife's out of town so I'm thinking Ramen
and uh and um and then I'm gonna take
our video and try to post it on YouTube
get all your pull requests in and I'll
probably send an email to kind of
everybody who expressed interest so
people who couldn't make it today can
um you know maybe contribute a poem or
watch it at their Leisure we'll see but
um I really appreciate you guys showing
up I really really personally appreciate
you helping with my little pet project I
hope it also helped you at the same time
um my hope is is that by the end of the
month we'll have the whole book in
um so that's it Simon any parting words
um yeah that I mean the main thing is
this stuff is really really convoluted
but the um the stuff that we've shown
you on GitHub specifically the um that
that github.dev thing is such a huge
leap forward in making this stuff
actually Pleasant to use so I I'm really
excited about it I think it it does make
this stuff a heck of a lot less painful
for people to get involved with mm-hmm
all right so I'll see you guys on GitHub
thank you Ben thank you Simon that was
awesome have a great weekend very much